rethinkdb.com 2011-11-08

# RethinkDB - Privacy Policy

Hexagram 49, Inc. (“RethinkDB”) operates rethinkdb.com. It is RethinkDB’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites. 

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, RethinkDB collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. RethinkDB’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how RethinkDB’s visitors use its website. From time to time, RethinkDB may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website. 

RethinkDB also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on the rethinkdb.com blog. RethinkDB only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below. 

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to RethinkDB’s websites choose to interact with RethinkDB in ways that require RethinkDB to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that RethinkDB gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up for a plan at rethinkdb.com to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with RethinkDB – by purchasing any RethinkDB plan, for example – are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, RethinkDB collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with RethinkDB. RethinkDB does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities. 

### Aggregated Statistics

RethinkDB may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, RethinkDB may monitor the most popular content on the rethinkdb.com site. RethinkDB may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, RethinkDB does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. 

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

RethinkDB discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on RethinkDB’s behalf or to provide services available at RethinkDB’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using RethinkDB’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. RethinkDB will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, RethinkDB discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when RethinkDB believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of RethinkDB, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an RethinkDB website and have supplied your email address, RethinkDB may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with RethinkDB and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. RethinkDB takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information. 

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. RethinkDB uses cookies to help RethinkDB identify and track visitors, their usage of RethinkDB website, and their website access preferences. RethinkDB visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using RethinkDB’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of RethinkDB’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies. 

### Business Transfers

If RethinkDB, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that RethinkDB goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of RethinkDB may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy. 

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, RethinkDB may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in RethinkDB’s sole discretion. RethinkDB encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change. 

_This privacy policy was based on Automattic's[privacy policy](http://automattic.com/privacy/), which was released under a Creative Commons Sharealike license._
